Humankind has developed so much that urban sprawl and intensive agriculture now dominate our landscapes.
人类发展如此之快，以至于如今地表满是扩张的城市和集约农业。
Unfortunately, with that comes the threat of climate change and a loss of biodiversity.
不幸的是，随之而来的是气候变化和生物多样性丧失的威胁。
What if we could return these landscapes to places that teem with wildlife, with ecosystems thriving as they did centuries ago?
如果我们能让这些地表景观回到数百年前那样，充满野生动物、生态系统繁荣的景象，会怎么样呢？
Since the 1980s, the concept of rewilding has increased in popularity.
自20世纪80年代以来，再野化的概念越来越受欢迎。
But what exactly is it, and what are the keys to its success?
但它到底是什么，成功的关键又是什么呢？
Put simply, rewilding is a technique that returns landscapes to a wilder, more natural state.
简单来说，再野化是一种让景观恢复更原始、更自然状态的方法。
It often involves reintroducing plants or animals that used to live there, but now don't.
它通常涉及重新引入过去曾生活在那里、但现在已消失的植物或动物。
Not-for-profit organisation Rewilding Europe says rewilding is "about letting nature take care of itself, enabling natural processes to shape land and sea, repair damaged ecosystems and restore degraded landscapes."
非营利组织"再野化欧洲"表示，再野化"关乎让大自然自我照料，让自然过程塑造陆地和海洋，修复受损的生态系统，恢复退化的景观。"
So, unlike traditional conservation techniques, the aim is to reduce the need for human intervention once the programme has been set up.
因此，与传统的保护技术不同，其目标是在项目建立后减少人为干预的需要。
In a 2021 article called 'Guiding principles for rewilding', one suggestion is to introduce plants, prey animals, and fungi first, so that when the top predator is introduced, they have an appropriate habitat to support them.
在2021年一篇题为《再野化指导原则》的文章中，一个建议是首先引入植物、猎物和真菌，这样当顶级掠食者被引入时，它们就有了适合的栖息地来供养它们。
Other tips are more people focused.
其他建议则更侧重于人的方面。
Even though rewilding is about reducing human presence in ecosystems, that doesn't mean we should be excluded from nature.
尽管再野化关乎减少人类在生态系统中的存在，但这并不意味着我们应当被排斥在自然之外。
The authors encourage compassion and learning from nature, rather than dominating it.
作者们提倡以同理心对待自然并向自然学习，而不是主宰自然。
They also say that, to avoid fear amongst rural communities that their farmland will be taken away, and that new predators will endanger their livestock, local people should be included so they have some control over the process and can directly benefit from it.
他们还表示，为了避免农民团体担心他们的农田会被夺走、新来的掠食者会危及他们的牲畜，应该让当地人参与进来，这样他们就能对这一过程有一定的控制权，并能直接从中受益。
Alex Stevenson owns Jordan's Farm in Essex, England and is rewilding her fields, hoping to help the ecosystem thrive.
亚历克斯·史蒂文森拥有英格兰埃塞克斯郡的乔丹农场，她正在将她的田地再野化，希望帮助生态系统繁荣发展。
She says, "I am rewilding to look after nature and to give life back to the soil" and adds, "you have to value nature because nature sustains us – we are part of it."
她说："我进行再野化是为了照顾自然，让土壤重获生机"，并补充道，"你必须重视自然，因为自然供养着我们——我们是自然的一部分。"